# Jasper van der Zwaan

A seasoned digital marketing professional with global experience

#### **PROFILE**

I am a seasoned digital marketing professional with extensive global experience in building, maintaining, and running successful digital, and traditional marketing campaigns.

Over the past 20+ years, I have implemented numerous large scale projects, including, websites, mobile & desktop applications, email campaigns, corporate branding, and omni-channel marketing initiatives.

I bring a rare amount of knowledge in visual design, user experience, typography, color theory, and creative problem solving skills to any business and/or clients I work with.

I have worked in various highly regulated industries, including; advertising, education, medical, insurance, finance, and mortgage origination.

I have extensive experience in usability, design iteration, A/B & multivariate testing to measure, and improve the performance of various web applications. I use artificial intelligence to help with research and ideation.

I'm able to take a vague concept on a napkin or formal requirements to a successful marketing strategy or product experience.

Highly experienced with Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, DreamWeaver, Premiere Pro & After Effects), Jira, Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, InVision, Zeplin, Salesforce, SFMC, and most other mainstream CMS/CRM tools.

Building strong, trusting relationships with peers and executives is vital to my approach. I have a proven track record in leading remote, off-shore, and in-office teams. Committed to lifelong learning; I continuously update my skills and sharing my accumulated wisdom whenever possible.



## **SKILLS**

- Design, passion, and curiousity.
- Multi-channel marketing & campaign management.
- Usability, design iteration, A/B, and multivariate testing.
- CMS, CRM, Digital, Content, and E-mail marketing.
- Advanced marketing analytics &
  KPI reporting.
- Effective communication, and collaboration abilities.
- Exceptional attention to detail.

#### CONTACT

jaspervdz@me.com +1 (805) 338-7681 Thousand Oaks, California www.jaspervanderzwaan.com

# Jasper van der Zwaan

A seasoned digital marketing professional with global experience

# **EDUCATION**

**BACHELOR OF ARTS - GRAPHIC DESIGN** 

Media College - Amsterdam, The Netherlands - September - 1995

FUNDAMENTAL & ADVANCED HTML CODING

Media College - Amsterdam, The Netherlands - August - 1996

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

PENNYMAC - Manager, Web Optimization

March 2019 - Present

- Developed & executed multi-channel digital media strategies, and roadmaps aligned with company growth and success goals.
- Closely tracked the latest digital marketing technologies, trends, and strategies to identify opportunities to enhance, and improve the business digital marketing roadmaps. Continuously evaluated company consumer-facing web properties, and executing on measurable optimization efforts by leading a highly effective testing team. Expert leader in ideating market relevant hypotheses, and, deep diving into analytics data to increase user engagement, in order to provide a steady stream of high converting leads for company sales teams.
- Juggled multiple high-visibility projects, and ensured quality & timely content delivery for multiple LOB's across the organization.
- Comfortable, and highly proficient in launching new, and maintaining existing consumer & B2B facing web solutions in a highly regulated business environment.
- Excellent working knowledge of most mainstream digital marketing tools such as: SFMC, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Chrome DevTools, Jekyll, Liquid, Yaml, etc. CMS: CloudCannon, LifeRay, WordPress, etc. G-Suite, MS Office Suite, Tableau, SnowFlake, Leadspedia, Rundeck, Jenkins, GitHub & AWS. Figma, Abobe Creative & Experience Suites, Screaming Frog, VWO, UserTesting, Optimizely, Target, HotJar, SEMrush, GA4, Tag Manager 360, etc.

#### AGIA AFFINITY - Manager, Digital Marketing 2014 - 2019

- Spearheaded client meetings to determine project needs and professional requirements and identify the correct course of action to help clients be successful.
- Maintained expert-level skills in digital platforms such as SalesForce Marketing Cloud, Adobe Creative Suite, Liferay CMS, Google Analytics, and Tableau.
- Drove digital and enterprise collaboration across functional teams, focusing on delivery and continuous process improvement.
- Devised strategies and roadmaps to support product vision and value to the business.
- Administered marketing calendar and posted new content to coincide with new product, and service releases.

# Jasper van der Zwaan

A seasoned digital marketing professional with global experience

# DAVID ALLEN COMPANY - Multimedia Designer 2012 - 2014

- Executed on new creatives for web, video, DM & printed materials that adhered to the overall creative vision and branding direction which resulted in 30% sales growth in 12 months.
- Oversaw all phases of video production for coaching talent promotional pieces, from pre- to post-production primarily using Premiere Pro, After Effects, and Media Encoder.
- Designed new treatments for display, online marketing, print, and packaging materials to further enhance company product branding strategies which resulted in 20%+ growth in those channels.
- Designed updated brand fundamentals. Created a new style guide/branding guide with updated typography, color palette, and new design approach to enhance company brand awareness.

# STERLING HEALTHCARE INFO SYSTEMS - Art Director 2008 - 2012

- Developed artistic visual products while working within defined technical guidelines.
- · Maintained accurate specs by adhering to print and art specification standards.
- Approved art layouts, copy design, and illustrative work for publication.
- Designed new on-brand visual elements to effectively convey concepts and messaging.
- Juggled multiple projects and tasks to ensure high-quality and timely delivery.

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE - Various Graphic & Motion Design Roles (USA & International) 1996 - 2009

• I will happily provide additional details regarding my previous work experiences beyond this time frame. (upon request).

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Pennymac MAP (Manager Accelerator Program), Thousand Oaks, CA.
- Pennymac PM Silver Certification, Thousand Oaks, CA.
- Google GTM Certified by LunaMetrics, Pittsburgh, PA.
- Google Adwords Certified by LunaMetrics, Franklin, TN.
- Tableau Desktop I: Fundamentals Certified by Tableau, Wexford, PA.
- Liferay Symposium NA 2015, Chicago, IL.
- GPS Leadership Training Certified by AGIA, Carpinteria, CA.
- HIPPA Compliance Training Certified by AGIA, Carpinteria, CA.
- GTD® Fundamentals Workflow Coaching Certified by David Allen Company, Ojai, CA.

# **WEBSITES**

- https://pennymac.com/
- https://corr.pennymac.com/
- https://tpo.pennymac.com/
- https://agia.com/
- https://gettingthingsdone.com/
- https://www.sterlinghcs.com/

### **LANGUAGES**

- English (Full professional proficiency)
- Dutch (Full professional proficiency)
- Flemish (Professional proficiency)
- German (Elementary proficiency)
- Spanish (Elementary proficiency)
- French (Elementary proficiency)